# MARK LOEGEL

#### CONTACT

269-271-2514

Madison Heights, MI meloegel@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/mark-loegel

https://markloegel.vercel.app/

https://github.com/meloegel

A full stack web developer that specializes in React RELEVANT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE and Node. My experience at Lambda school has given me confidence shipping modern web applications on cross-functional development teams. I have a passion for programming and enjoy the pursuit of new technologies.

## TECH STACK

- · Core Skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Git
- Front End: React, Redux, Context, MaterialUI, ReactStrap, MapBox, React-Map-GL, PlotlyJs, Ant Design, SemanticUI
- Back End: NodeJS, Knex, Express, PostgresSQL, SQLite3, GraphQL, MySQL
- Testing: Cypress, Jest and Supertest and React Testing Library
- · Experience with Docker, RESTful API, Unit testing, npm, yarn, SASS/LESS

#### SKILLS

- Agile Project Management
- Analyze complex technical information
- Design, analyze and implement database structures
- Team leadership
- Pair-programming
- · Remote work and remote learning

# **EDUCATION HISTORY** LAMBDA SCHOOL

Web Development & Computer Science, 2020

- Produced numerous production quality web applications
- · Experience with agile software development methods
- Participated in the Lambda Leadership program
- Part of the Lambda X Endorsement program

# OAKLAND UNIVERSITY

Psychology with Focus in Child Development, 2012 Member of Swimming and Diving Team, 2008-2012

- Division 1 Program
- Conference Champions all 4 years

# PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE

Collaborative Advantage Marketing Building/Construction Manager | 2017-2019 Goldfish Swim School Franchising Operations Consultant | 2015-2017 Goldfish Swim School Rochester/Macomb Manager On Duty | 2013 - 2015

# BRIDGES TO PROSPERITY | OCT 2020 | BRIDGESTOPROSPERITY.ORG **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

# NODE | EXPRESS | JEST | REACT | ANT DESIGN | MATERIAL UI | MAPBOX | PLOTLY

- Worked on a cross-functional team of 4 data scientists and 4 web developers over 4 weeks to display data generated by the Data Science team on a map for the stakeholder to better be able to evaluate new and existing bridge site locations
- Added topography and different icons to the map functionality
- Integrated new output from our data scientist's model into our backend API service
- Updated the styling of the app to match the current web site
- With my personal updates of adding topography and adding graphs with PlotlyJs our version of the project was chosen to continue to build on by the stakeholder

# ULTRAMIKRO | NOV 2020 | ULTRAMIKRO.VERCEL.APP

### FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

#### REACT | MATERIAL UI

- Contracted to recover what was possible from previous site and create and deploy new site
- Originally created the project in HTML in approximately 3 days. Deployed May 2020
- Re-created the site in React in Oct in approximately 3 days. Deployed Oct 2020
- Stakeholder happy with new site, remain in contact for future updates of the site

# **PROJECTS**

# CONWAY'S GAME OF LIFE | 2020 | GITHUB REPO | DEPLOYED LINK FRONT END DEVELOPER

# REACT| SASS | JEST

- · Created Conway's Game of Life(CGOL) in React in a week
- Built a version of CGOL in Python. This project was made using React and was a great opportunity for me to hone my JS skills

# RUN TRACKER | 2020 | GITHUB REPO FE / BE | DEPLOYED LINK **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

# NODE | EXPRESS | POSTGRES/SQLITE | JEST | REACT | SASS | MATERIAL UI | CYPRESS

- Created an app that will track running times and can publish runs to a public feed
- Back End uses Jest for Testing, Front End uses Cypress
- Back End is deployed on Heroku, Front End on Vercel

## BUILD WEEK - HOW TO | 2020 | GITHUB REPO

### **BACK END WEB DEVELOPER**

#### NODE | EXPRESS | POSTGRES/SQLITE | JEST

- Created the Back End for the project
- Favorite project while at Lambda, loved learning how to write an elaborate and well documented readme

# BUILD WEEK - WATER MY PLANTS | 2020 | GITHUB REPO

# FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

# REACT | YUP | STYLED-COMPONENTS | FORMIK

- Created entirety of Front End of app with exception of login and register
- · Worked closely with the Back End engineer to help plan out the database schema

# BUILD WEEK - ANYWHERE FITNESS | 2020 | GITHUB REPO

# FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

REACT | YUP | STYLED-COMPONENTS

- Worked on a project with many different cohorts in a group of 9
- Collaborated across different teams to complete this project, worked in a group with Data Scientist and an iOS Team to deliver the product on time.